《诉讼双雄》前情提要
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
你想要我的哪一个客户
Which one of my clients are you after?
我们都清楚你拿不走辉瑞制药
Because we both know you can't have Pfizer.
首席翻译官
█ 网易见外
-不  我可以  -你得让我当冠名合伙人
- Yes, I can. - Then make me name partner.
你不能为了拉个客户就随便把
You don't just slap somebody's name on the wall
某个人名字拍上墙
to get a client.
我不仅仅是把他的名字拍上墙  路易
I'm not just slapping his name up, Louis.
首席校对官
人人译视界
·
人人
我在做正式动议
I'm making a move.
我不是说你不应该提拔唐娜
I'm not saying Donna doesn't deserve a promotion;
翻译     Océano  Alex  苏葵  烟雨忆江南  小溪1120
我只是想说成为合伙人意义重大
I'm just saying making partner means something.
而我担心这个先例
And I'm concerned that being one here
会破坏这个意义
won't mean what it used to.
翻译     Giggles  斗斗  克里斯托啊托  大能  木浅
这可是很大的工作量
This is an amazing amount of work.
我熬了一整夜
I stayed up all night doing it.
我以为昨晚轮到你陪儿子
But I thought you take the night shift with your son.
校对     木浅  某羽
我告诉我妻子昨晚她来接替我
I told my wife she'd have to take it last night.
我想你可能需要一些方式来缓解
I thought you might need a little relief.
确定吗  托住他的头
You sure? Support his head.
时间轴     张小满   Caroline
好的
There we go.
该死  戈登不是真的想掌权
Holy shit. Gordon really doesn't want to take over.
他是想争取一个让他的人
He just wants to orchestrate a deal
后期     斯人
回来的交易
where his guys come back,
让他们投票和赞恩合并
they vote to merge with Zane,
我们就不存在了
and we cease to exist.
总监     木浅
我刚发现我的两个合伙人
I just found out that my two partners
居然背后捅我刀子
are willing to stab me in the back.
该死  路易  我正想尽一切办法帮助公司
God damn it, Louis. I'm trying the best I can.
┌
┐
└
┘
人人影视官方客户端
唯一下载渠道
app.YYeTs.com
┌
┐
└
┘
那试试别的吧
Well, then, try something else,
因为在我们冲下悬崖
because giving you the reins
提前半小时把控制权给你
a half hour before we drive off a cliff
一点用都没有
isn't gonna do shit.
我只是来确认你的客户
I just came to make sure that the paperwork was in order
加入我们新公司的所有文书都准备好了
for your clients to come over and join our new firm.
我今天去找安迪·福赛斯了
I went and saw Andy Forsyth today.
你去找他谈了关于西雅图工作的事吗
You went to see him about us moving to Seattle?
如果我们还想尝试这种事
If we're ever gonna do something like this in our lives,
现在就是最好时机
now is the time.
那婚礼怎么办
And what about the wedding?
我们可以提前
We could move it up.
我唯一知道的
If I've learned one thing,
就是只要你在我身边
it's that there is nothing that I can't handle
就没有过不去的坎
when I have you by my side.
你是我见过的最坚强的男人
You're the husband I've always wanted.
我已经等不及和你开始冒险旅程
And I can't wait to begin our adventure together.
瑞秋和我得到了工作邀约
Rachel and I were offered a chance
去西雅图管理律所
to run a firm in Seattle.
-迈克  -哈维
- Mike-- - Harvey,
我就是这样的人  我一直都是
this is who I am. It's who I've always been.
到时候了
It's time.
我告诉你  罗伯特
I'll tell you what, Robert.
你宝贝女儿刚结婚
Your baby girl just got married,
我就可怜可怜你
I'm gonna throw you a bone.
把你名字放在前面
Your name goes first.
不  不
No. No.
别以为我不知道你打的什么主意
You think I don't know what you're doing.
让我欠你人情  你名字放前面吧
Then I owe you. Yours goes first.
你是说让我欠你人情吗
You saying I owe you?
你本来就欠我  我帮了你大忙
You do owe me. I saved your ass.
你之所以这么做
Well, you only did that
是因为我们当时让你很难做
because we put you in a terrible position.
等等  找错理由了
Wait. That's against me.
天呐  我这是摊上什么事了
Jesus Christ, what have I got myself into?
我可以回答你
I'll tell you what.
你成了赞恩-斯佩克特-利特律所的合伙人
You got yourself into Zane Specter Litt.
斯佩克特-赞恩-利特律所也行
Or Specter Zane Litt.
不管怎样...
Either way...
利特放最后
Litt comes last.
想出去吃个汉堡吗
Wanna go out and get a burger?
想  但现在是凌晨两点
I do. But it's 2:00 A.M.
如果我现在出去吃汉堡
If I go out for a burger right now,
我就等着老婆跟我离婚吧
the only thing I'm getting is a divorce.
懂了  我从厨房给你拿一个
Copy that. I'll get you one from the kitchen.
好  我们楼下见
Yeah, meet me downstairs.
把它藏在礼品袋里什么的
Hide it in the gift bag or some shit.
-你来得真早  -是啊
- You're here early. - I am.
我知道你这个时候会晨跑完
I know this is about the time you finish your morning run.
听着  哈维  如果是因为你不在时
Look, Harvey. If this is about me
我和路易吵架的事...
getting into it with Louis while you were gone--
不是这事  其实你没说我都不知道
It isn't. I didn't even know that happened.
那我现在就告诉你事情经过
Well, you might as well hear about it now.
我想到一个可以拯救律所的想法去找他
I came to him with an idea to save the firm
就是让我暂时成为经营合伙人
that involved making me temporary managing partner
碰了我一鼻子灰
and he bit my head off.
我猜猜  他以为你想夺我的权
Let me guess, he thought you were coming after me.
哈维  我绝不会这样对你
Harvey, I would never do that to you.
我知道  但我来这里是为了别的事
I know that, but that's not what I'm here to talk about.
我来是要告诉你就在今早
I'm here to tell you that as of this morning
我们要和罗伯特·赞恩律所合并了
we're merging with Robert Zane.
-什么  难以置信  -亚历克斯
- What? I don't believe it. - Alex.
我当时来的时候你说
When I came over you said
我会成为下一个冠名合伙人
my name would be the one to go up next.
我记得
I know that,
但这是拯救律所唯一的选择
but this was the only way to save the firm.
你和我都清楚
And you know as well as I do,
赞恩当冠名合伙人的时间
Zane has been a name partner
比我和路易加起来都长
longer than me and Louis combined.
好吧  我理解
All right, I get it.
但是我们有言在先
But we had an agreement.
我现在需要你向我保证你会履行承诺
And I want your word right now that you're gonna honor it.
我向你保证  你会是下一个冠名合伙人
You have my word. Your name goes up next.
好吧
All right.
还有一件事
One more thing.
今早之前路易知道要合并的事吗
Did Louis know about the merger before this morning?
对啊  怎么
Yeah, why?
因为如果他没告诉我
Because if he didn't tell me about it,
他就真的太不信任我了
he must really not trust me.
也就是说真到了要提名我的时候
Which means when it is time to put my name up there--
你不用担心路易  亚历克斯
Louis'll be fine, Alex.
万一我要担心呢
And what if he's not?
正如我说的  我向你保证
Like I said, you have my word.
为了你我当然会的
Of course I would do that for you.
我会为你做任何事  因为我爱你
I would do anything for you because I love you.
我答应你  我再也不提了
I promise. I will never bring it up again.
我们绝不养缅因猫
We never have to get a Maine Coon.
-是希拉  -是的
- Sheila? - Yes.
我让你进来是因为
Anyway, I brought you in because I want--
卡特里娜  你怎么了
Katrina, what's on your mind?
没什么  只是  你要放弃养猫
Nothing. It's just, giving up cats?
路易  她让你遭了那么多的罪  你确定吗
Louis, after all she put you through, are you sure?
确定呀  再说了
I am. And besides,
她还在考虑接受短发呢
she's still open to getting a short hair.
-那我可真为你开心  -我也为你开心
- Well, then I'm happy for you. - And I'm happy for you, too,
因为今天
because today is the day that
你要把你最喜欢的两件事做的干净利落
you get to make your two greatest loves more efficient.
省省吧  我们正要和赞恩合并
Don't tell me. We're merging with Zane;
我们的新律师数量超过了合理数量
we have more associates than we can handle;
你需要一个
and you need the one person
在两家公司都呆过的人来精简人员
who worked at both firms to cull that herd.
正是如此  你现在给我起草一份
Exactly. And now I need you to come up
有着十个最没效率的初级员工的名单
with a list of the ten least-efficient associates
不用告诉我名字  也不用说
without telling me names or whether or not
他们是赞恩的人还是我们的人
they come from Zane or us.
明白
Got it.
还有  卡特里娜
And, Katrina?
谢谢你对我和希拉的关心
Thanks for your concern about Sheila and me.
路易  你知道我是在乎你的
Louis, you know I care for you
与性别丝毫无关
deeply in a completely asexual manner.
我也非常在乎你
And I too care for you deeply
同时把你当作中性的存在
and see you neither as man nor woman.
谢谢你  路易
Thank you, Louis.
我从没听到过比这更好的嘉奖
Kinder words were never spoken.
今天我会把名单给你
I'll have my list for you by the end of the day.
我也会想她的
I'm gonna miss her too.
我说不好哪个更糟
I'm not sure which is worse.
到底是发现迈克是个骗子
Finding out Mike was a fraud
还是他要把我的女儿带走
or that he's taking my daughter away.
要我说还是骗子那事儿
Pretty sure it was the fraud thing.
有道理
You probably got a point.
说到骗子和你女儿
Speaking of frauds and your daughter.
这是她留给我的
She left that for me?
来自你家小宝贝的小小欢迎礼
A little welcome to the firm from your little girl.
哦对了  哈维要开个会
By the way, Harvey wants to meet at
九点半在会议室
9:30 in the conference room.
乘这段时间
So in the meantime,
你不如在迈克的老办公室先拾掇拾掇自己
why don't you set yourself up in Mike's old office.
谢了  唐娜
Thank you, Donna.
有你是我们的荣幸  罗伯特
It's nice to have you here, Robert.
想想就刺激  我还能告诉哈维
Oh, we'll see how nice it is once I tell Harvey
我可不要他的老办公室
it's not his old office that I'm looking to be in.
都已经开始以执行合伙人的身份说话了
Claiming managing partner already.
第一天上任你这是不是太狂了点
Isn't that a bold statement for day one?
我告诉你  红发妞
Let me tell you something, Red.
我这辈子就全靠说狂话了
I've been making bold statements my entire career.
老子现在可停不下来了
I'm sure as hell not about to stop now.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
♪ See the money, wanna stay for your meal ♪
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
♪ Get another piece of pie for your wife ♪
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
♪ Everybody wanna know how it feel ♪
*所有人都想见见那景象*
♪ Everybody wanna see what it's like ♪
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
♪ I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind ♪
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
♪ Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money ♪
*好了*
♪ All right ♪
*退开点  我要跳舞*
♪ All step back, I'm 'bout to dance ♪
诉讼双雄 第八季 第一集
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
♪ The greenback boogie ♪
我想大家都了解谁将成为执行合伙人
All right, I think we all know who's gonna be managing partner
不是一个草率的决定
isn't something we're gonna decide overnight.
因此  为了公司的和谐
Therefore, for the sake of firm harmony,
我们首先从利益冲突出发
I suggest we start with conflicts of interest.
-我不介意  -我也是
- Fine with me. - Me too.
很好  你们都很清楚
Great. As you can see,
我擅自选出了一个
I've taken the liberty of suggesting
你们需要放弃的客户列表
who drops which client.
我相信你们会赞同我的提议
And I am confident you'll agree with all of my proposals
-除了  -我不会放弃德科斯特洛
- with the exception-- - I'm not dropping Dexterol.
我不会放弃克拉维坦
And I'm not dropping Clavatin.
-正是如此  -正是什么
- Exactly. - Exactly what?
你说的  正是什么  想说明什么
What do you mean, "Exactly what?"
我知道你俩都不愿意
I knew that neither of you would be willing
放弃这几个特定客户  我正是这个意思
to give up those particular clients. Exactly that.
你的意思是你没有个建议吗
You mean you don't have a suggestion?
我有个提议
I have a suggestion.
你先放弃你的  下次我们
You drop yours, then the next time
有重大冲突时  我再放弃我的
we have a major conflict I'll drop mine.
你确定  下次的重大冲突
You sure about that? Because the next major conflict
可是我俩谁将成为执行合伙人
we're gonna have is who's managing partner.
那你到底是什么意思
Then what exactly is your idea?
要我说  谁的客户占了
I say whoever's client billed
上年最多时长的留下
the most hours last year stays.
这还真他妈方便
Well, that's pretty damn convenient
你的客户刚完成了一项合并
because your client went through a merger
他们付的钱可是在飞涨
so their billables are inflated.
你是说太阳把你给闪瞎了
You're saying that the sun got in your eyes
所以你把到嘴的肥肉弄丢了
and that's why you dropped the big pass?
等等  哈维说得对
Wait a second, Harvey's right.
-又来  -不  跟放弃哪个客户无关
- Come again? - No, not about who to drop.
你的客户刚完成了一项合并
Your client did just go through a merger.
他们开发了一个全新的产品
They're in a whole new line of business.
大部分产品与克拉维坦不再有交集
Most of which doesn't conflict with Clavatin anymore.
你要说什么
Where you going with this?
我是说如果我们能说服两边客户
I'm saying if we can get either client
各放弃一个他们重叠的部门
to drop the one division where they still overlap
你们就都能保留住自己的客户了
you can keep them both.
如果是这样的话  我去说服我的客户
Well, in that case I'll get my client to drop.
这是我最起码能做的
It's the least I can do.
不  让我来吧
Oh, no. I'll do the honors.
毕竟是你邀请我来你的公司
After all, you welcomed me into your home.
不如我们打个小赌
Why don't we make it a friendly wager.
分头去说服各自的客户
We each get our client to drop.
先成功的人赢
First one who gets there wins.
说定了
Sure thing.
别这么做
Don't do it.
做什么
Don't do what?
别在告诉赞恩你会说服你的客户之后
Don't try to get Zane's client to dump their division
又试图让他说服他的客户放弃
after telling him you'd get your client to do it.
你怎么知道刚才发生了什么
How do you even know that's what happened?
我知道是因为路易告诉我的
I know because Louis told me.
什么叫路易告诉你的
What do you mean Louis told you?
会议差不多两秒前才结束
The meeting just ended two seconds ago
然后我直接就过来了
and I came right back here.
如果是这样  那我的意思是
In that case, I mean,
我从会议室里一个不存在的录音机里
I heard Louis' voice on the recording device
听到了路易说的话
that I had installed in the conference room.
你窃听了我们的会议
You bugged the meeting?
窃听这个词太没有品味了
Bugged is such a distasteful word.
-这没有回答我的问题  -好吧
- That's not an answer. - Okay.
你想知道真相吗
You want an answer?
从你是做助理律师开始
I have been listening to your conversations
我就一直偷听你的谈话  现在也一样
since you were an associate and I'm not about to stop now.
现在你是想继续挑剔我的做法
Now, do you want to quibble about my methods
还是想听听我是如何
or do you want to get the part
从你的错误中拯救你呢
where I save you from yourself?
-唐娜  -哈维  你听到他说的了
- Donna. - Harvey, you heard him.
赞恩垂涎着执行合伙人的位置
Zane's got his eye on managing partner.
我很清楚他想要什么
I know good and well what he's after.
那你为什么要给他这个机会
Then why would you give him ammunition?
因为你觉得这会很有趣
Because you think this is gonna be fun.
但相信我  你对他出手
But trust me, you go after him
后果会比你想象得严重的多
and it's gonna get more serious than you thought.
到最后  你只能证明
And in the end, you're just gonna prove
他比你更适合坐你的位置
that he's better suited to be in your office than you.
好的  唐娜
Okay, Donna.
"好的"是指你不会和罗伯特·赞恩作对吗
Okay, you're not gonna pick a fight with Robert Zane?
不  是指我会找个人替我和他作对
No. Okay, I'm gonna find someone else to do it for me.
一天见两次
Twice in one day.
这次又是什么风把你吹来了
To what do I owe the pleasure now?
我是来告诉你
I'm here to tell you,
如果你想做冠名合伙人  就要自己争取
you want your name on the door you got to earn it.
我以为已经争取到了
I thought I already had.
也许是  也许不是
Maybe you have, maybe you haven't,
但我有工作交给你
but I got something for you to do anyway.
具体是什么工作
And what exactly is that?
我需要你去说服罗伯特·赞恩最大的客户
I need you to get Robert Zane's biggest client
卖掉他们的生产部门
to sell their manufacturing division.
哈维  你给我指了一条上山的路
Harvey, you point me up the hill,
我会不留余力干掉山顶的人
I'm gonna kill whoever's at the top.
-但是  -但是这一回
- But? - But in this case,
在山顶的是自己人
the guy at the top is on our side.
-是吗  -你在说什么
- Is he? - What are you talking about?
我是说  这要取决于谁真正管理律所
I'm telling you this is gonna determine who runs the firm.
赞恩和我都知道这点
Zane knows it and I know it.
所以如果你希望我能如期兑现我的承诺
So if you want me to be able to live up to that promise,
我需要你搞定这事
I need you to do this.
我不喜欢你用
And I don't like being threatened
自己已经承诺的事情威胁我
for you to uphold a promise you already made.
我也不喜欢  不管你是否愿意
I don't either, but like it or not,
这对我们俩都有好处
this benefits both of us.
而且我向你保证
And I guarantee you right now,
赞恩也正找他的副手做同样的事
Zane's going to his right-hand man to ask the same thing.
那么谁是他的副手呢
And who is his right hand?
你的工作不是问他是谁
Your job isn't to ask who he is.
而是打败他
Your job is to kick his ass.
你近期有搬进新公司的计划吗
You planning on making it in to the new offices anytime soon?
为什么  帮你挑选新台灯吗
What for? Help you pick out new lamps?
这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
这意味着我知道你会过来
It means I knew you'd come in here
让我在恰当的时间去搞定
and ask me to take care of whatever needs taking care of
需要搞定的事情
whenever it needs taking care of.
除非你想进来打一回合
So unless you want to step in and take a beating,
不如你就直说吧
why don't you just get to it?
你以为我打不过你吗
You think I couldn't handle you?
我想如果你松开领带
I think if you took your tie off,
我们就能一决高下
we could find out.
该死  如果我上去被一个瘦弱的
Shit, I come up there and get my ass kicked
白人女孩打败  我这人就丢大了
by a skinny white girl, my life would never be the same.
现在什么情况  一个二号一个六号吗
So what do we got? A number two, a number six?
十四号和十一号侧边
Number 14 with a side of 11.
把文件和细节留下
Well, leave the file and the particulars,
-等我结束就去看  -萨曼莎
- I'll get to it when I'm done. - Samantha.
我需要你帮我度过这个关卡
I need you to come through for me on this one.
拜托  罗伯特  我什么时候让你失望过
Come on, Robert, have I ever let you down before?
你从没输过
You've never lost,
但你确实有一两次让我失望
but you have let me down a time or two.
好吧  那我向你保证
Well, then, I give you my word
这次不会让你失望
this will not be one of those times.
该死  她绝对能打败我
Damn, she could kick my ass.
卡特里娜  你在这里干什么
Katrina, what are you doing here?
-我给了你一个任务  -我完成了
- I gave you an assignment-- - I finished it.
什么叫你完成了
What do you mean you finished it?
我让你评估50名助理
I asked you to evaluate 50 associates.
你怎么可能这么快就做完了
How could you have done that already?
我没做  PATTIE帮我做的
I didn't. PATTIE did it for me.
-PATTIE是谁  -不是谁  是什么
- Who the hell's Pattie? - Not who, what.
个人评估计数和个人效率总计
Personal Assessment Tallying and Totalling Individual Efficiency.
你在说什么
Say what now?
我插入了16个可量化参数
I plugged in 16 parameters and quantifiables,
PATTIE弹出了一个从第一到
PATTIE popped out a list
第五十名排序的名单
ranking the associates from 1 to 50.
卡特里娜  这太疯狂了
Katrina, this is amazing.
不止如此  而且完全客观
Not only that, it's completely objective.
最后十名是效率最低的  起码现在是
The bottom ten are the least efficient, period.
那我猜就只差最后一步  你告诉我
Well, then I guess all that's left is for you
他们是谁  然后由我辞退他们
to tell me who they are and for me to let them go.
关于这个  路易
About that, Louis.
我想亲自处理辞退的事
I'd like to be the one to do the letting go.
卡特里娜  我决不会要求你做那样的事
Katrina, I could never ask you to do that.
不是你要求我  是我自己要求
You're not asking; I am.
我不明白  你为什么想那么做
I don't understand. Why would you want to?
路易  你说过有一天我会成为高级合伙人
Louis, you told me I could be senior partner one day.
那就意味着  我得有能力去做这样的事
Which means, I need to be able to do things like this.
-但是  -就像内德·斯塔克说的
- But-- - And as Ned Stark would say,
"判人死刑必应亲自操刀"
"He who passes the sentence should swing the sword."
你知道我从不会质疑内德·斯塔克
You know I can never argue with Ned Stark.
我知道
I do.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡特里娜
Katrina.
-办得利落点  -我会的
- Make them clean deaths. - I will.
杰里米·斯蒂勒
Jeremy Stiller.
-你是哪位  -我为罗伯特·赞恩办事
- Who are you? - I work for Robert Zane.
抱歉  "为罗伯特·赞恩办事"女士
Ah. Well, I'm sorry Ms. Works for Robert Zane,
这里是私产区
but this is private property.
我不得不请你离开
I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
我不得不说  你看上去就像
I have to say, it almost feels like you knew
知道我会来找你一样
this encounter would happen.
那是因为亚历克斯·威廉姆斯告诉我
That's because Alex Williams told me
有个叫萨姆·惠勒的男士会来这儿
a man named Sam Wheeler would be coming.
那就是说他神通广大到
Which means he was resourceful enough
能查得到我的名字  但少了点想象力
to find out my name but didn't have enough imagination
没能想到我可能是个女的
to think I might be a woman.
是么  他可是有足够的想象力
Well, he had enough imagination
提醒我别接你的电话
to tell me not to take your call.
他那么做的原因是因为他害怕
And he only did that because he's afraid
你会喜欢我要说的话
you might like what I have to say.
并不会  即使我会喜欢
Well, I don't. Even if I did,
我对斯佩克特·利特绝对忠诚
I'm loyal to Specter Litt.
听着  我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
我们显然开了个坏头  但是我
Clearly we got off on the wrong foot, but I--
的确如此  如果你不介意的话
We did. Now if you don't mind,
我得工作了
I have work to do.
我生长于贫苦之家
I grew up poor.
我们住在农场上  我上大学的唯一机会
We lived on a farm and my only chance
就是靠获得奖学金
of going to college was to get a scholarship,
而我的确拿到了
which I did.
大二那一年  设立我奖学金的
Sophomore year, the company that funded my scholarship
公司破产了
went out of business.
所以我只有一条路
So I had a choice.
自己挣钱  或者辍学
Do it myself, or don't do it at all.
从那以后  我所拥有过的一切
Since then, I have scratched and clawed
都是我拼尽血泪而得
for everything I have ever had.
为什么要告诉我这些
Why are you telling me this?
因为我知道虽然细节可能有所不同
Because the details were different
但我们的境遇其实很像
but I know the same thing happened to you.
拜托了
Please.
我只求你能听我把话说完
All I'm asking is for you to hear me out.
好 我听你说
Okay, I'll hear you out.
但是我绝不会停掉我的生意
But there's no way I'm dropping my business.
唐娜  你有空吗
Donna, do you have a minute?
是和我们裁员的事
Does this have to do with the associates
-有关吗  -没错
- we're letting go? - It does.
自从我知道你要跟他们
And since I understand you'll be doing
进行离职谈话
exit interviews with them,
我想你应该知道要走的人都是谁
I thought you should know who's going.
有意思
That's funny.
这不是我原以为你你要提的事
That's not what I thought you'd be asking.
什么意思
What do you mean?
卡特里娜  你确定亲自开掉曾经和你
Katrina, are you sure you're going to be okay
共事数年的人对你来说没问题吗
firing people you've worked with for years?
我知道你很珍视公司  但是这
I mean, I know you value you the firm, but this--
我知道这不会好受  唐娜
I know it isn't going to be easy, Donna.
我也曾经被迫离开过这里
I was once let go from here too,
但是我要告诉你我和路易说的话
but I'll tell you what I told Louis.
如果我要在这里演好自己的角色
That if I'm going to grow in my role here
这就是我必须学着去做的事之一
this is something I'm going to have to learn to do.
说得好
Fair enough.
等一下  路易看过这个名单吗
Hang on a second, has Louis seen this list?
还没  怎么了
No, why?
名单上的第一个人大有问题
There's a problem with the first name.
-他会不高兴的  -我知道
- He's not gonna like it. - I know that.
我建议你在动手之前
Then I suggest you let him know
最好提前知会他一声
before you pull the trigger.
-我不能那么做  -为什么
- I can't do that. - Why not?
因为整个过程应该是公平公正的
Because this process is supposed to be impartial.
如果就因为路易不会喜欢某个名字
And if I tell Louis who I'm going to fire
出现在名单上我就要提前透露给他
just because he won't like one of the names on the list--
我不会喜欢什么
What won't I like?
路易  卡特里娜只是来通知我
Louis, Katrina was just informing me
你可能不太会同意...
that it's not a good idea for you--
谁的名字
What name?
-布莱恩  -不行
- Brian. - Nope.
路易
Louis.
唐娜  这是我和卡特里娜之间的事
Donna, this is between katrina and me.
不  路易
No, Louis, it isn't.
这事关公司和公司的诚信
This is about the firm and its integrity.
你让我想出一个客观衡量标准
You asked me to come up with an objective metric
而依据这个标准  布莱恩·阿特曼必须走
and by that metric, Brian Altman has to go.
-那就调整标准  -我做不到
- So change the metric. - I can't do that.
即使我可以
And even if I could
他也不一定合格
he'd be just as likely to go down as go up.
我明白  但我不在乎
I understand that, but I don't give a shit.
-除了布莱恩谁走都行  -路易
- Anyone but Brian. - Louis--
卡特里娜  听我说
Katrina, listen to me.
你想承担这份职责
You asked for this responsibility
我答应了  现在我告诉你
so I gave it to you. So now I am telling you
想办法留住他
to find a way to keep him.
好吧  路易  我尽力而为
Okay, Louis. I'll see what I can do.
哈维  我们得谈谈
Harvey, we need to talk.
别告诉我有麻烦了
Don't tell me, there's a problem.
-确实有  -是什么
- There is. - What is it now?
不是什么大事
It's not that big of a deal,
但你得想好用什么字体
but you're gonna have to figure out what font to use
把我的名字加进冠名合伙人
to put my name on the letterhead.
今天下午2点起  罗伯特·赞恩的客户
Because as of 2:00 p.M. Today, Robert Zane's client
就要正式关掉他们的制造部门
is officially dropping their manufacturing division.
你是说你做到了
You telling me you did it?
签字  盖章并交付了  老兄
Signed, sealed, and delivered, my man.
现在我们来想好...
Now let's get down to figuring out--
想什么  如何拆我的上一招吗
What? How to counter my last move?
因为你们可能已经签字盖章了
Because you may have them signed and sealed
但我来告诉你们  交付中途夭折了
but I'm here to tell you your delivery got lost on the way.
-你是谁  -她叫萨姆·惠勒
- Who the hell are you? - Her name is Sam Wheeler.
老实说  亚历克斯  还是叫我萨曼莎吧
Truth be told, Alex, I prefer Samantha.
你俩认识吗
You two know each other?
不  但傻瓜都知道
No, but it doesn't take a genius to figure out
-她是赞恩的人  -他就不知道
- she's Zane's guy. - He didn't figure it out.
我知道的是  不管你是谁
What I figured out is, whoever you are,
如果你认为你可以大摇大摆走进我办公室
if you think you can waltz into my office--
-哈维  我能处理  -是吗
- Harvey, I got it. - Do you?
因为除非是我搞错了状况
Because unless I'm misreading the situation,
-否则她就是在说你不能  -哈维
- she's saying you don't. - Harvey.
我看你俩明显有点矛盾
You know what, you two are obviously having some trouble.
好消息是你们有足够时间
The good news is you'll have plenty of time
来化解矛盾  因为今天下班后
to work it out because as of end of business today,
你们的客户就要关掉他们的制造部门
your client is dropping their manufacturing division.
然后我们就可以开始
And we can get back to the business of running
在罗伯特·赞恩的指导下经营律所了
this firm under the direction of Robert Zane.
祝你们俩今天过得...
You two have a nice--
你们知道我没那个意思
You know I don't mean it.
不要
No.
-不要是什么意思  -我是说这是我的战斗
- What do you mean, no? - I mean this is my fight.
你叫我参与作战
You asked me to fight it,
而我不会让你在第二回合中途插足
and I'm not gonna let you step into the middle of round two.
现在或许是第二回合中途
It may be the middle of round two,
但你刚才告诉我  你在第一回合就赢了
but you just told me you got a first round knock-out.
我错了  但我还在拳击台上
Well, I was wrong. But I'm still in the ring,
我的合伙人名头命悬一线  而我不会退出
my partnership's on the line, and I'm not getting out.
-那你最好打赢  -你去哪里
- Then you better win. - Where you going?
开始我这个重量级的战斗
To pick a fight in my own weight class.
罗伯特  怎么样  安顿好了吗
Robert, how are you? Settling in all right?
一切顺利  多谢关心
Doing just fine, thanks for asking.
有什么事吗
What can I do for you?
我顺便过来告诉你
I just dropped by to tell you I had
我刚和你的萨姆姑娘谈了场有趣的对话
an interesting conversation with your girl, Sam.
她完胜了你  对吗
She's kicking your ass, isn't she?
不是我  因为你们俩
Not mine. Since neither of you
都没胆量邀请我上场
had the balls to invite me into the ring.
你也没邀请我
Just like you didn't invite me.
而且别说什么我们有约之类的屁话了
And don't give me any of this nonsense about we had a deal.
因为你违约和我一样快
Because you broke it just as fast as I did.
没错  但我的问题
I did, but my issue isn't
不是她在替你作战
that she's fighting your battles for you.
而是她走进我的办公室
It's that she walked into my office like
就像我不是这间律师的经营合伙人一样
I wasn't the managing partner of this firm.
我也不喜欢
And I didn't like the way
她向我自我介绍的方式
she introduced herself to me either.
但你的问题不在于此
But that's not what your issue is.
你生气
You're pissed.
是因为我没有亲自上场
Because I didn't get in the ring myself.
因为如果我不上场  你就不会上场
Because if I'm not in there, you're not in there.
而你无法忍受不能亲自作战
And you can't stand not being in there.
你是说我总是必须射门吗
Are you saying I always have to shoot?
因为我也可以传球
Because I'm fine passing the ball.
我是说做教练
I'm talking about being a coach.
如果你是一名教练  就不会介意
And if you were one, you wouldn't mind
坐在场下  看着萨曼莎·惠勒
just sitting back and watching Samantha Wheeler
把你的人打得落花流水
eat your boy for breakfast.
要是你认为事情会如此进展
And if you think that's gonna happen,
那是你还不了解亚历克斯·威廉姆斯
you don't know Alex Williams.
我当然知道事情会如何进展
Oh, I know that's what's gonna happen.
你不了解的人是哈维·斯佩克特
And the person you don't know is Harvey Specter.
我很了解自己
I know myself just fine.
那就告诉我你不会掺和这事
Then tell me you'll stay the hell out of this.
没问题  我刚向亚历克斯保证我不会插手
No problem, I just gave Alex my word I'd stay out.
要是无法履行自己的承诺
And what kind of managing partner would I be
我还算什么经营合伙人
if I couldn't live up to my word.
因为  跟你说清楚  罗伯特
Because, just so we're clear, Robert,
-我是经营合伙人  -随你怎么说  哈维
- I am managing partner. - Whatever you say, Harvey.
但是记住  你不再只是
But remember, you didn't only
给了亚历克斯·威廉姆斯承诺
give your word to Alex Williams anymore.
你还对我作了承诺
You just gave your word to me.
后来我就发现...
And the next thing I knew...
豌豆弄得到处都是
There were peas everywhere!
我身上  墙上
On me, on the wall,
到处都是  就是没进他嘴里
everywhere but in his mouth.
-我告诉你  那真是... -好恶心
- I'm telling you, it was-- - Disgusting.
我想说可爱的  但是...
I was gonna say adorable, but...
总之  真不错
Anyway, this is nice.
卡特里娜  我很高兴你邀我吃午餐
Katrina, I'm glad you suggested lunch.
布莱恩  请你谈谈
So tell me, Brian.
你认为有了小孩
Do you think that having a baby
能让你做更多的工作吗
has made you more productive in the workplace?
-你在开玩笑吗  -我明白了
- Are you kidding me? - I see.
那你的效率怎么样
Then what about your efficiency?
我知道孩子有时会迫使
I understand children sometimes necessitate
一个人提高时间管理能力
better time management skills.
对我妻子来说可能是  但我告诉你
For my wife, maybe. But to tell you the truth,
我已经焦头烂额了
I'm all over the place.
那你在哪方面
Then what would you say
做的不错呢
are the areas where you do excel?
-关于照顾孩子吗  -不  我指工作
- With my son? - No, Brian. At work.
老天  我要被炒了吗
Oh, my God. Am I getting fired?
什么  没有
What? No.
我们就是聊聊孩子
We were just talking about babies,
这让我想到
and it got me thinking--
我的时间管理能力吗
About my time management skills?
卡特里娜  别瞒我了  我听到风声了
Katrina, don't lie to me. I've heard the rumors.
我是这次合并中要被辞掉的吧
Am I one of the ones being let go from the merger?
没错  布莱恩  我们是在精减人员
You heard right, Brian. We are making some cuts.
但你要知道这完全是根据
But you should know the decisions were based
客观数据的
on completely objective data.
完全客观的吗
Completely objective?
我对公司任劳任怨
I work my ass off for this firm.
你的数据可不是这么说的
Well, your numbers certainly don't show that.
-我的数据  -对
- My numbers? - Yes, your numbers.
反映你工作努力程度的数据
The thing that indicates how hard you work.
我无法相信
I don't believe this.
也许人们关于你的评价是对的
You know what, maybe people were right about you.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
他们说你冷酷
It means they say you're cold
你只关心你的工作
and all you care about is your job.
或许说的对  你可能就是一部机器
Well, maybe they're right. Maybe you are a robot.
你怎么敢这么说我
How dare you say that to me.
我怎么不敢这么说你
How dare I say that to you?
我给你看了我孩子的照片
I've been showing you pictures of my child
但你一直在等着给我下解雇通知
and the whole time you've just been waiting to fire me.
正常人会这么做吗
What kind of person would do that?
你知道吗  我在努力
You know what, the kind of person
找出一个保住你的方法
who's been trying to figure out how to save your job.
但我完全没找到任何理由
But I haven't heard one thing that I can use
让我留住你
to justify keeping you.
所以我决定  你被解雇了
So as far as I'm concerned, you're fired.
路易  能和你谈谈吗
Louis, Can I talk to you for second?
当然  怎么了
Course, what do you need?
有件事我想让你做
I have something I want to run by you.
我想先听听你的意见
I need to know if you think it'll work.
发生了什么
What's going on?
哈维想让赞恩的客户
Harvey's trying to get Zane's client
精简部门  而不是我们的
to drop their division, not ours.
赞恩也在这么做
And Zane's doing the same thing.
我猜你站在哈维这一边
Let me guess,you're on team Harvey.
-没错  -你有什么计划
- Exactly. - What's your plan?
非常棒
I love it.
你觉得这不会导致触发禁令吗
You don't think there's an end around for her with an injunction?
除非她单方面提出申请
The only way she could do that if she filed an ex-parte motion.
但时效已过
Which she can't do retroactively.
亚历克斯  这棒极了
Alex, this is brilliant.
起诉需要我帮忙吗
Do you need help filing it?
不 路易  我已经申请了
No, Louis. I already did.
我只是确保没有遗漏
I was checking to make sure I didn't miss anything.
亚历克斯
Hey, Alex.
哈维和我说  你觉得我仍在生你气
Harvey told me that you thought I was still mad at you
因为赞恩的事我没有告诉你
because I didn't come to you about Zane.
其实不是  依我而看
That's not true. As far as I'm concerned,
你是我们这边的  一直都是
you are on our side. You always will be.
时机到时  我会支持你做冠名合伙人
When the time comes, I'll back you as name partner.
非常感谢  路易
I appreciate that, Louis.
去拿下他们
Go get 'em.
布莱恩  我正想去
Hey, Brian, I was just about to come--
-找我吗  一派胡言  -你是什么意思
- See me? Bullshit. - What do you mean bullshit?
我是说你根本不会去找我
I mean there's no way you were gonna come see me
因为你连当面给我解雇通知都不敢
because you didn't even have the balls to fire me to my face.
什么  布莱恩  没人要解雇你
What? Brian, nobody's firing you.
那你看着我
You're gonna look me in the eye
告诉我  卡特里娜没有玩数字游戏
and tell me that Katrina didn't run her numbers
来断定我工作不够努力
and determine that I don't work hard enough to serve this firm?
- 不 那不是  -你知道吗
- No, that's not-- - You know what?
起码你可以亲自告诉我
If you'd at least come and told me yourself,
但我也不指望你那么做
but why should I expect something like that?
毕竟  你抱过我的孩子也算不上什么
After all, it's not like you ever held my newborn son.
布莱恩  等一下
Brian, please wait.
我让卡特里娜想办法保住你
I told Katrina to find a way to keep you
因为你的价值远超过你工作的范畴
because I believe you are more than worthy that you of serving this firm.
而且我确实关心你
And I do care about you and that is the truth.
也许你的确和她这么说
Yeah, well, maybe you did tell her all that,
但也无法阻止她解雇我
but it didn't stop her from firing me anyway.
-布莱恩  -你知道吗  路易
- Brian-- - You know what, Louis?
如果你需要  之后两天我会把
If you need me, I'll be spending the next two days
我的文件整理好
getting my files in order.
和卡特里娜的分析恰恰相反
Because contrary to Katrina's analysis,
我关心我的客户  而且我是个称职律师
I care about my clients, and I'm a damn good lawyer.
路易  在你开口前
Louis, before you say--
你到底有什么毛病
What the fu-- is your problem?
你公然藐视我给你的任务
I gave you an order and you blatantly ignored me.
我没有
I didn't ignore you.
那布莱恩的事你怎么说
Then what do you call firing Brian
我明确地说过不要解雇他
when I specifically told you not to?
听我说  我是想保住他
Listen to me, I tried not to fire him.
-我约他一起吃午餐  -午餐  真棒
- I took him to lunch, and we-- - Oh, good, lunch.
我希望鸡肉派很好吃
I hope the chicken potpie was delicious.
但你依旧没照我说的做
You still didn't do what I asked.
你知道吗
You know what?
我确实做了你原先要求的事
I did do what you originally asked.
就是客观的评价各位律师
To objectively evaluate the associates.
而非关照你的"老师宠儿"
Not coddle your teacher's pet.
我才不管我原先要你做什么
Screw what I originally asked.
我让你重制标准以留下一名有价值的律师
I told you to rejigger the metrics to keep a valued associate.
你以为我最开始没有尝试过捏造数据吗
You think fudging the numbers wasn't the first thing I tried?
这不管用
It didn't work.
-他的分数总是太低  -我不在乎
- He always came out too low. - I don't care.
可我在乎  因为我关心这家公司
Well, I do. Because I care about this firm.
重制标准这件事会让那些
And what kind of message does rejiggering the metrics
一周工作上百小时的律师怎么想
send to the associates who work 100 hours a week,
他们每晚都是在公司吃晚饭啊
who eat dinner here every night,
他们连约会都没有  更别说生孩子了
who don't even go on dates, let alone have a baby.
我不管他们会怎么想  卡特里娜
I don't care what message it sends, Katrina.
布莱恩必须留下
Brian is staying.
那让谁当他的替罪羊你自己想辙
Then you figure out who goes instead.
因为我不会做我不相信的事
Because I'm not doing something I don't believe in.
不  卡特里娜
No, Katrina.
我告诉过你一次  今日我再说一次
I told you once and I'm telling you again.
是你要求的这份工作  那就你来做
You asked for this job; you are doing it.
哈维
Harvey.
你得看一眼这个
You need to take a look at this.
-是什么  -刚来的案子
- What is it? - It just came in.
这是一份销售合同草案  是给克拉维坦的
It's a proposed contract of sale for Clavatin's--
制造部门  他奶奶的
Manufacturing division. Son of a bitch.
我要知道托马斯法官在哪儿  立刻
I need to find out where judge Thomas is and I need to find out now.
哈维  你不能绕过亚历克斯行事
Harvey, you can't do this without Alex.
这是他的案子
It's his case.
那为什么告诉我这事的是你不是他呢
Then why the hell are you the one telling me this and not him?
因为他很可能正在外面奋斗
Because he's probably out there fighting
因为他认为他还能赢
because he thinks he can still win.
有一件事他想对了
Well, he's got one thing right.
我们确实还能赢  但他不行
We can still win. But he can't.
你现在架空他  你也赢不了
And if you cut him out, you won't win either.
你觉得我打不赢萨曼莎·惠勒吗
You think I can't take Samantha Wheeler?
我是觉得你好像说过不愿插手此事
I think you said you'd stay out of it.
而且如果你现在接手  还不通知亚历克斯
And if you take over now without even telling Alex,
那你就自己去找托马斯法官吧
then you can find out where Judge Thomas is yourself.
因为我才不要替你通知你的队友
Because I'm not gonna help you tell your own team
你要架空他们  就为了战胜萨曼莎·惠勒
that you'll cut them out just to get the better of Samantha Wheeler.
你要是想告诉亚历克斯我要做什么
Look, you want to tell Alex what I'm doing?
尽管去说  我才不要袖手旁观看我们败诉
Go ahead. I am not about to sit on the sidelines and watch us lose.
哈维
Harvey.
我只问你这一次
I'm only gonna ask you this once.
有没有可能是你对迈克离开这事反应过度
Is there a chance you're that overreacting to Mike having just left?
我不知道  唐娜
I don't know, Donna.
但实话告诉你吧  我不在乎
But to tell you the truth, I don't care.
好吧
Okay.
你赢了
You win.
我去找托马斯法官在哪儿
I'll find out where Judge Thomas is.
心情真是沉重
Heavy is the head.
尤其是不得不做的事有失公允时
Especially when what has to be done is unjust.
你还是不认为布莱恩
You still don't think that Brian
应当留下来  是不是
deserves to stay, do you?
确实如此
No, I don't.
而当我告诉路易
And when I told Louis that
这样做会让那些拼命工作比布莱恩
it would send the wrong kind of message to the people
更为公司卖力的人产生错误的想法时
who work their asses off for this firm a lot more than Brian,
他说他不在乎
he said he didn't give a shit.
我懂了
I see.
路易不明白的是
And what Louis didn't understand was
你口中的人们可不是随便什么人
that the people you're talking about weren't just people.
-而是你自己  -你怎么能
- It was you. - How could you--
因为我知道倾尽全力却仍然不被重视
Because I know what it's like to give everything
是什么感受
and still be taken for granted.
不论如何
And for what it's worth,
我认为路易那么说是错的
I think Louis was wrong to say what he did.
但布莱恩的事他可没错
But he isn't wrong about Brian.
-可我不同意  -我理解
- Well, I don't agree. - I understand that.
这可能和去年你告诉哈维
Probably has something to do with why you told Harvey
我不该成为合伙人的原因有关吧
that I shouldn't be made partner last year.
-你知道这事  -现在知道了
- You knew about that? - I do now.
-唐娜  那不是...  -告诉我
- Donna, it wasn't-- - Tell me.
你为路易管理所有的数据
You ran all the numbers for Louis,
前五名最有效率的律师都有谁
who are the top five most efficient associates?
杰西  莎拉  莱恩  卡尔  吉娜
Jesse, Sarah, Ryan, Carl, and Gina.
-布莱恩坐哪儿  -就这里
- Where does Brian sit? - Right here.
就在这五人中间吗
Right here in the center of those five people?
你觉得这是巧合吗
Do you think that's a coincidence?
-我从...  -卡特里娜
- I had-- - Katrina.
有件事你要明白  有些人
What you have yet to learn is that there are players
从不显山漏水  但大家都需要这样的人在
who never put up great stats, but you keep them around
因为他们会让周围的人做得更好
because they make the people around them better.
你说的是布莱恩还是你
Are you talking about Brian or you?
两者都有
I'm talking about both.
那我该怎么办
So what do I do?
该怎么办就怎么办
You do what you said you'd do.
你评估各位律师
You evaluate the associates.
不过这一次  做得再好一点
Only this time, do it better.
对不起  唐娜
I'm sorry, Donna.
我不该去找哈维的
I shouldn't have gone to Harvey.
没事  卡特里娜
It's okay, Katrina.
我看中的本来就是首席运营官的位置
COO is where I'm meant to be.
-哈维  -亚历克斯
- Harvey. - Alex,
-在你张口之前  -不  你保证过
- before you say anything-- - No, you gave me your word
你不会插手此事的
that you were gonna stay out of this.
结果刚一转头  你就在我不在场的情况下
The next thing I know, you're having a meeting
跟我的委托人会面
about my client without me.
首先  那是我的委托人
First of all, it's my client.
可这是我的案子
And it's my case.
而你就要输了
Which you were about to lose.
-只是受挫而已  -胡扯
- It was a setback. - Bullshit.
你让人耍的溜溜转
You were getting your ass kicked.
-还不告诉我真实情况  -去你的  哈维
- And don't tell me you weren't. - God damn it, Harvey.
听我说亚历克斯  这女人可不是开玩笑的
Listen to me, Alex. This woman is no joke.
你是说我是个玩笑吗
You saying I am?
我的意思是我刚见过托马斯法官
I'm saying I just met with Judge Thomas,
所以我非常清楚如何击败她
so I know exactly what it's gonna take to beat her.
所以呢  你可以玩阴的我也可以啊
So the hell what? I can play dirty just as well as you.
你或许可以  但是我承诺过
Maybe you can, but I gave you a promise
我会让你成为冠名合伙人  但如果你
to put your name on the wall.
为了战胜罗伯特·赞恩的副手耍花招
And if you play dirty to beat Robert Zane's right hand,
-那你别想了  -你知道我在想什么吗
- it isn't gonna happen. - You know what I think?
我在想这听起来就像一个刚愎自用
That sounds like some bullshit by a guy
一意孤行的家伙扯出来的鬼话
who's just gonna do what he wants like he always does.
亚历克斯  我想要的是继续当经营合伙人
What I want, Alex, is to stay managing partner.
事情也将会如我所愿的发展
This is the way that's gonna happen.
-哈维  我--  -够了
- Harvey, I-- - That's enough.
接下来由我接管
I'm taking it from here.
事情解决了
It's done.
卡特里娜  我今早吃了很多
Katrina, I've got a lot on my plate this morning.
所以  如果你不介意的话
So if you don't mind--
你只想喝杯咖啡  我明白
You just want your morning coffee, I know.
这也是你效率考核的一部分吗
Was that part of your efficiency evaluations?
咖啡摄入量
People's coffee consumption?
听着  布莱恩  我错了
Look, Brian, I was wrong about you.
我明白你为公司做过什么
I understand what you do for the firm
我很抱歉我说了那些话
and I'm sorry for the things I said.
我欣赏你的坦诚  但如果你这么说
Well, I appreciate that, but if you're just saying this
-只是因为路易让你--  -我不是
-because Louis told you to-- - No, I'm not.
而且他也没有告诉我什么
And he didn't.
那你为什么说这个
Then why are you saying it?
因为我是希望它能让我有所成长
Because I took this assignment hoping
才接的这个任务
that it would help me grow.
但如果我需要帮忙的时候都不敢求助的话
And if I can't ask for help when I need it,
那我的成长空间比我想的还要大
then I have even more growing to do than I thought.
你说的求助是指什么
What do you mean ask for help?
我对助理律师们进行的考核是有缺陷的
My evaluation of the associates was flawed.
我没有考虑到一些不确定因素  所以
It didn't take into account intangibles, and...
我希望你能帮我修改一下
I was hoping you could help me fix that.
你的意思是  你希望我来决定
You mean you want me to help you figure out
不炒我了之后炒谁
who to fire instead of me.
不  布莱恩  我不是那个意思
No, Brian, that's not what I meant.
你就是  而且我确信
Yes, it is. And I'm sure firing
炒掉我的同行们对公司十分有价值
my fellow associates is a value to the firm,
但我不会帮你的
but I'm not gonna help you do it.
-你他妈做了些什么  -我什么也没做
- What the hell did you do? - I didn't do anything.
除了我做了的事之外
Well, except for the thing that I did.
你指去找托马斯法官
You mean going to Judge Thomas
让他听取一些编造的伪证
and having him allow fabricated testimony
以驳回我的动议
to overrule my motion.
证词不是编造的  不过被听取了是真的
It wasn't fabricated, but it sure as hell was allowed.
你是怎么做到让他听信的
And how exactly did you get him to do that?
你要么知道我怎么做到的  要么不知道
You know how I did it, or you don't.
而如果你不知道的话  我也不打算
And if you don't, well, I'm not about
把我的战术告诉你
to open up my playbook and show you.
行啊  油嘴滑舌先生  我他妈才不管
Well, Mr. Slick, I don't give a shit
你怎么做到的  因为我会撤销它
how you did it. I'm going to undo it
因为这案子还没完
because this is isn't over.
-不  它已经完了  -我们等着瞧
- Yes, it is. - We'll see about that.
不  我们不用瞧
No, we won't.
因为我要给你一道直接命令
Because I'm giving you a direct order.
我命令你不能采取任何行动
You are not to take any action
以改变这次事件的结果
to affect the outcome of this situation.
随你怎么给我命令
And you can give me all the orders you want.
我只听罗伯特·赞恩的命令
The only person I answer to is Robert Zane.
所以如果你想阻止我的话
So if you want to stop what I'm about to do,
最好在我做到之前去找他谈
you better talk to him before I god damn do it.
-你敢就这么走开  -吃屎去吧
- Don't you walk away from me. - Kiss my ass.
好了  罗伯特  我已经很有耐心了
All right, Robert. I have been patient,
但是事情已经了解了  而且我赢了
but it's over, and I've won.
召回你的狗吧
Call off the dogs.
你他妈刚刚和我说什么
What the hell did you just say to me?
我说召回你的狗  我不希望我自己的
I said call off the dogs. I'm not gonna have someone
公司里有人连自己败局已定都看不出来
inside my own firm who doesn't know when she's lost.
公司里唯一看不出来自己败局已定的人
The only one in here who doesn't know
是你
that they've lost is you.
我什么都没败
I didn't lose shit.
如果你觉得我可能会失败的话
And if you think I might, why don't you pick up the phone
你为什么不打给托马斯法官呢
and call Judge Thomas right now?
我说的不是托马斯法官
I'm not talking about Judge Thomas.
那你他妈说的是什么
Then what the hell are you talking about?
我说的是你曾在这里信誓旦旦的说
I'm talking about the fact that you stood right here
你不会掺和这件事
and gave your word that you would stay out of this thing.
现在你不但背弃了诺言
And not only did you break it,
甚至还想让我一起掺和进去
now you're in here trying to drag me into it.
没话说了  那就对了
Nothing to say? That's right.
也许你赢了场战役  但是你输了战争
You may have won the battle, but you lost the goddamn war.
因为你刚向整个公司展示了
Because you just showed this entire firm
咱们其中只有一个人具有管理才能
only one of us is managing partner material.
而那个人  不是你
And it isn't you.
这是我的公司
This is my firm,
我不会让你夺走它
and I'm not gonna let you take it.
告诉你个秘密吧  哈维
I'm gonna let you in on a little secret, Harvey.
它已经是我的了
I already have.
现在我建议你消化一下
Now, why don't you let that rattle around
等你意识到我说的话是对的了
for a little while, and then come back
再回来告诉我
when you're ready to tell me that I'm right.
你可以进来的
You can come in, you know.
-抱歉  我不想--  -你想
- Sorry, I didn't mean to-- - Yes, you did.
你只是想让我
You just wanted to let me finish
把手头的工作做完
whatever I was in the middle of.
不错嘛
Not bad.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
不  我是谢谢你在卡特里娜那替我说话
No, I mean, thanks for sticking up for me with Katrina.
-你发现了  -我发现了
- You figured it out. - I did.
我没看错你
I was right about you.
你难道不是从来没看错过人吗
Aren't you right about everybody?
嗯  基本上是吧
Yeah, pretty much.
现在还有一件事我也没看错
And now I have something else to be right about.
卡特里娜需要你的帮助
Katrina needs your help.
也许她需要  但是一想到
Maybe she does, but if I'd thought
我继续留在公司意味着
about the fact that me staying would mean
我在乎的人会被炒鱿鱼
someone I care about might get fired...
我就不会去找路易了
I wouldn't have gone to Louis in the first place.
这恰恰证明了我们留下你是个正确决定
And that, right there, is the reason we were right to keep you.
在我看来
And as I see it...
你要么帮卡特里娜做出正确的决定
You can either help Katrina make the right decision,
要么就得忍受她可能做出的错误决定
or live with the fact that she might make the wrong one.
就像她差点炒了你一样
Like she almost did with you.
哈维  我能为你做些什么
Harvey, what can I do for you?
我来告诉你你本该为我做什么
I'll tell you what you should have done for me.
阻止我从亚力克斯那里接下这桩案子
Stop me from taking the case from Alex.
你回想一下  我当时就是这么做的
And if you recall, that's what I tried to do.
但后来你又改了主意
And then you changed your mind.
因为我听了你的话
Because I listened to you.
你可真会挑时候
Oh, well, you picked a hell of a time
听我的话  因为赞恩给我设了陷阱
to start doing that because Zane set me up.
我才不管赞恩做了什么
I don't care what Zane did,
你去找她斗  是因为你本性如此
you went after her because it's who you are.
但你应该救我免于受困于我的本性
And you're supposed to be saving me from myself.
我就是这么做的
Which is exactly what I did.
你是凭什么才这么想
How the hell do you figure that?
哈维  迈克走了
Harvey, Mike left.
迈克走了和这有什么关系
What does that have to do with this?
息息相关
It has everything to do with this.
因为迈克离开的原因就在于
Because the reason he left is because
他终于开始接受真实的自己
he finally came to terms with who he is.
现在他走了
And now that he's gone,
而你  是个想重回游戏场的人
who you are is a man who wants back in the game.
难道你还不明白  你已经到达山顶了
Don't you see, you've been to the top of the mountain.
你已经证明了自己可以做到  也许你
You've proved you can do it, and you may not
不想承认  但是
want to admit it, but...
你已经厌倦仅仅待在山顶
you're getting tired of just sitting up there,
欣赏美景
enjoying the view.
唐娜  如果我往山下走
Donna, how's it gonna look
别人会怎么想
to the rest of the world if I step down?
我来告诉你他们会怎么想
I'll tell you how.
那就是没有一家公司能和我们比肩
Like no other firm can touch us.
因为你讲和罗伯特做那些
Not with you and Robert doing what everybody knows
大家知道你们会做的事
you were meant to do.
而我指的是
And by that...
意思是做到那些
I mean pulling off the kind of shit
只有哈维·斯佩克特才能做到的事
that only Harvey Specter can do.
卡特里娜
Katrina.
-你找我  -是的
-  You wanted to see me? - Yes.
布里奇特  请坐
Bridget, please sit down.
我要被开除了吗
Am I getting fired?
是的  很抱歉
Yes. I'm afraid you are.
卡特里娜  我知道我们合并了
Katrina, I know we merged,
但我有很大一笔学生贷款要还
but I have a ton of student debt.
我的房东刚涨了租金  而且
My landlord just raised my rent, and...
我还答应要付我侄子的日托费
I promised to pay for my nephew's daycare
为了让我姐姐回学校读书
so my sister could go back to school.
求求你了
Please.
我一定还能做些什么
There's got to be something I can do
争取能再有一次机会
to get a second chance.
抱歉  布里奇特
I'm sorry, Bridget,
但是我们已经做好决定了
but the decision's already been made.
祝你好运
I do wish you the best of luck.
这还是我办公室时  生活要简单多了
You know, life was simpler when this was my office.
就我所知  你在这间办公室那会儿
As I understand, when you were in this office
差点为了迈克·罗斯进监狱
you almost went to prison for Mike Ross.
我看不出这种生活怎么更简单了
I don't see what was simpler about that.
不  你看得出
Yeah, you do.
罗伯特  你说如果我愿意承认
Robert, you said that I should come back
你是对的  我就应该回来
when I was ready to admit that you were right.
现在我回来了
Well, I'm back.
要承认这点不容易  哈维
Takes a big man to admit that, Harvey.
我很感激
I appreciate it.
你不会是想给我一个拥抱吧
You're not gonna try to hug me, are you?
我不知道你和路易什么关系
I don't know what goes on between you and Louis,
但我就算了
but I'll pass.
我猜接下来就该我
Then I guess this is the part where I make
向我无所畏惧的领导提出卑微的请求了
my first humble request to my fearless leader.
才两秒就要提要求了
That took about two seconds.
说说看
Let's hear it.
我的办公室
My office.
-怎么了  -我想要回我的办公室
- What about it? - I want it back.
这样的话  你无所畏惧的领导
In that case, your fearless leader
很乐意应允
is happy to comply.
我们出去吃点汉堡  你觉得怎么样
What do you say we go out and grab those burgers?
今晚不行  以后有的是机会
Not tonight, but we will.
我还有些事情要处理
I still have something I have to take care of.
-你说得对  -什么事说得对
- You were right. - About what?
开人不是件容易的差事
It wasn't easy firing those people.
-所以你的工作做完了  -完了
- So it's done? - It's done.
你介不介意我问问  布莱恩最终
You mind if I ask if Brian ended up
有没有帮你确定名单
helping with this list?
他帮了
He did.
你也没看错他
And you were right about him too.
既然我们在纠结我看的没错的那些事
Well, as long as we're handing out "You were rights,"
你去开除那些人也是对的
You were right about being the one to let those people go.
你是说这有助于我成长
You mean it's good for my growth.
不  我是说很高兴我不用去做这些事
No, I mean, I'm glad I didn't have to do it.
这项工作太糟了
It sucks.
你想喝一杯吗
Hey, you want to grab a drink or something?
-好啊  -卡特里娜
- I'd love to. - Katrina.
罗伯特
Robert.
让我和唐娜谈谈  好吗
Give me a second with Red here, will you?
当然  我在我的办公室等你
Of course. I'll be in my office.
我有麻烦了吗
Am I in trouble?
为什么这么说  你做什么坏事了
Why, you do something wrong?
这取决于你怎么定义坏事
I guess that depends on what you mean by wrong.
我来不是找你麻烦的
I'm not here because you're in trouble.
我来是因为哈维刚刚找我换办公室
I'm here because Harvey just asked me to swap offices
还承认说我是对的
and then he told I was right.
我看那个男人如果不是
And I doubt those words have ever come out
先问了你  恐怕绝无可能
of that man's mouth without first having
说出这种话
a conversation with you.
作为一个进来不到十分钟的人
You sound pretty sure of yourself for a man
你好像略有点自信了
who's only been here about ten minutes.
你以为瑞秋就不会跟她爸爸提起
You think Rachel didn't tell her father
非凡的唐娜·鲍尔森吗
about the mighty Donna Paulsen?
我从来没觉得她是爱八卦的人
Guess I never thought of her as much of a chatterbox.
不过  她确实跟我提起过你当年...
Then again, she did tell me about the time that you took--
不管是什么事  你要记住
Whatever it is. Just remember,
一旦你说出来
once you say it out loud,
我们就没办法假装你我不知道了
we can never pretend that you don't know it.
而这  罗伯特·卢卡斯·赞恩
And that, Robert Lucas Zane,
就是你应该当经营合伙人的原因
is why you are managing partner.
-晚安  唐娜  -晚安  罗伯特
- Good night, Donna. - Good night, Robert.
你真是不懂什么叫界限
You really have no concept of boundaries, do you?
换做普通人  这会儿肯定
You know, most people would be here
要跟你说我们的第一次见面不顺利
to tell you they think we got off on the wrong foot.
但我来是想说  我觉得很顺利
But I'm here to say we got off on the right one,
哪里顺利了
And what foot is that?
因为我们发现了
The one where you and I discover
你我其实很像
we're not so different after all.
我觉得我和你毫无相似之处
I don't think I'm anything like you.
有的  比如我们都是
You are. Right down to the fact
在纽约  河滨市长大的
that we both grew up in Riverside, New York.
所以不管我们赢得多少尊敬
Which is why we'll both always feel like outsiders
在这里都不会有家乡的感觉
no matter how much we earn their respect.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that about me?
因为我会调查
Because I do my homework.
也许我们确实很像
Maybe we are alike.
那么我想说的说完了
That's all I wanted to say.
除了一件事
Except for one thing.
你跟杰里米·斯蒂勒说你在农场长大
You told Jeremy Stiller that you grew up on a farm,
但据我所知  河滨市没有农场
and last I checked there aren't any farms in Riverside.
而能知道这一点恰恰证明
And that little observation is the reason
我们对对方的第一印象不错
we got off on the right foot.
我不懂
I don't follow.
我跟不同的人编造
There are three things that happen
我的不同经历时  有三种可能
when I tell different people different stories.
其一  他们听不出来错误
One, they don't recognize it.
也就是说我不用在意他们
Which means I don't need to worry about them.
其二  他们知道
Two, they know I did it,
但是没有勇气指出来
but don't have the balls to say anything.
也就是说他们连第一种都不如
Which means I need to worry about them even less.
而其三  就是他们直接戳穿我
Or three, they call me on it.
相信我  我只看得上这种人
And believe me, three is my kind of guy.
这样的话  欢迎你来我们公司
Well, in that case, welcome to the firm.
我很荣幸
Glad to be here.
对了  我本来也能赢的
Oh, and by the way, I would have won.
亚历克斯
Alex.
晚上十点了  你干什么呢
It's 10:00 at night; what are you doing?
我要看萨曼莎·惠勒的所有案件记录
I'm going through every one of Samantha Wheeler's files.
因为大战要来了  我要做准备
'Cause a fight's coming, and I'm gonna be ready.
听我说
Okay, listen to me.
相信我  我曾经也这样过
Because, believe me, I've been where you are before.
别做什么之后会后悔的事
Don't start something that you'll regret later.
那我该怎么做
Then what am I supposed to do?
不如现在交个
How 'bout you make a friend now
以后能给你好处的朋友
that you'll be happy about later.
你疯了吗  她才不想当朋友
Are you crazy? She's not looking to make friends.
也许  但亚历克斯  你听我说
Maybe not, but, Alex, listen to me.
长远看来  这个女人也没戏
In the long run, this woman is going nowhere.
我和哈维都在你这边  你胜券在握
Got Harvey and me on your side. You get the trifecta,
不管她干什么  在你面前都没戏
I don't care what she does. Never gonna beat you again.
你是建议我去拍罗伯特·赞恩的马屁吗
Are you suggesting I kiss Robert Zane's ass?
-我可没这个打算  -不  亚历克斯
- 'Cause I'm not gonna do that. - No, Alex.
我只是说去了解了解他
I'm just saying get to know the man.
你建议我怎么做
And how exactly would you suggest I do that?
这要看你  我只是碰巧知道
That's up to you. I happen to know
他玩高尔夫  你也玩
the man plays golf. So do you.
要是换做我  就从这里入手
If it were up to me, I would start right there.
请自便
Make yourself at home.
谢谢
Don't mind if I do.
既然你来了那我就说两句
Well, as long as you're here.
你做到了  一如既往
You came through, like always.
-谢谢  萨曼莎  -一如既往
- Thanks, Samantha. - Like always.
你不是说  我也让你失望过吗
What happened to, "You let me down a time or two"?
好了  你知道有时候我不会说话
Come on, you know I get like that sometimes.
怎么了  你有心事
What's going on? Something on your mind?
是的  我完成了你的要求
Yeah, there is. I did what you asked and
-现在我有要求了  -什么要求
- now I have something to ask. - What's that?
我不想只当你的迈克尔·克莱顿
I don't want to just be your Michael Clayton.
我想要更多
I want more.
-可我已婚  -好了  罗伯特
- I'm married. - Come on, Robert.
你知道我想要什么  时机到了
You know what I want, and it's time.
萨曼莎  我们谈过这件事的
Samantha, we've been over this.
你当上冠名合伙人  就不能再像
You get name partner, and you're not going to be able
你以前那样行事了
to operate the way you always have.
意思是我不能再帮你收拾烂摊子了
You mean I won't be able to clean up your messes.
你收拾的可不只是我的烂摊子
My messes aren't the only ones you clean up.
恐怕一半时间你都在收拾你自己的吧
I believe you spend half the time cleaning up your own.
我这几天是在收拾我的烂摊子吗
Oh, is that what I spent the last few days doing?
-萨曼莎  -罗伯特  我要冠名合伙人
- Samantha? - Robert, I want name partner.
今年之内就要
And I want it before the year is out.
否则呢
Or what?
今年之内  罗伯特
Before the year is out, Robert.